{"Topic": "Music and Dance", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "In which creative art is Sonal Mansingh distinguished?", "op1": "Dance", "op2": "Vocal music (Hindustani)", "op3": "Painting", "op4": "Instrumental music", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a \u2018classical\u2019 dance form?", "op1": "Kalaripayattu", "op2": "Chhobia", "op3": "Bhawai", "op4": "Kathakali", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which among the following is a martial dance?", "op1": "Kathakali", "op2": "Bamboo dance in Meghalaya", "op3": "Chhau of Mayurbhanj", "op4": "Bhangra of Punjab", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Match List I with List II and select the correct answer using the code given below the lists.", "op1": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 3; D - 4", "op2": "A - 4; B - 3; C - 1; D - 2", "op3": "A - 2; B - 4; C - 1; D - 3", "op4": "A - 4; B - 1; C - 3; D - 2", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "de:", "op1": "traditional dance of Kerala", "op2": "special food prepared in Tamilnadu", "op3": "boat race of Kerala", "op4": "dress worn in Karnataka", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Koodiyattam is a", "op1": "Bharatnatyam", "op2": "Kuchipudi", "op3": "Odissi", "op4": "Kathakali", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "With which of the following dances Raja Reddy is associated with?", "op1": "Punjab", "op2": "Haryana", "op3": "Uttar Pradesh", "op4": "Uttarakhand", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "\"Gidda\" is a popular folk dance from which state of India?", "op1": "Bhangra", "op2": "Bharatanatyam", "op3": "Chhau", "op4": "Wangala", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which from the following is a \"Classical\" dance form?", "op1": "Manipur", "op2": "Kerala", "op3": "Mizoram", "op4": "Himachal Pradesh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Chakyar Koothu is a performing art associated with which of the following states?", "op1": "Garba", "op2": "Dandiya", "op3": "Jhumar", "op4": "Kathak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a folk dance of Rajasthan?", "op1": "Andhra Pradesh", "op2": "Kerala", "op3": "Karnataka", "op4": "Tamil Nadu", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Kuchipudi is a dance drama of which of the following States?", "op1": "Shovana Narayan", "op2": "M. S. Subbalakshmi", "op3": "Pt. Jasraj", "op4": "Hari Prasad Chaurasia", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who amongst the following is renowned in Hindustani classical music (vocal)?", "op1": "Shehnai", "op2": "Tabla", "op3": "Sitar", "op4": "Santoor", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Alla Rakha was an exponent of which of the following instruments?", "op1": "Hindustani Classical Music", "op2": "Instrumental Music", "op3": "Urdu Poetry", "op4": "Kathak Dancing"}, {"Question": "Dr. M. S. Subbulakshmi has distinguished herself in the field of", "op1": "Kathak", "op2": "Bharatha Natyam", "op3": "Playing Violin", "op4": "Vocal Music", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not correctly matched?", "op1": "Ravi Shankar - Sitarist", "op2": "M. F. Hussain - Tabla", "op3": "R. K. Narayan - Novelist", "op4": "Kaifi Azmi - Poet", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "With which of the following instruments is Anuradha Pal associated?", "op1": "Sitar", "op2": "Veena", "op3": "Tabla", "op4": "Mandolin", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Mohini Attam dance form was developed in :", "op1": "Andhra Pradesh", "op2": "Karnataka", "op3": "Kerala", "op4": "Tamil Nadu", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The theory of classical music is discussed in :", "op1": "Samaveda", "op2": "Yajurveda", "op3": "Rigveda", "op4": "Atharvaveda", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Rukmini Devi Arundale was associated with which of the following forms of classical dances?", "op1": "Bharat Natyam", "op2": "Kuchipudi", "op3": "Odissi", "op4": "Kathak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Kalbelia is a folk dance associated with which of the following states?", "op1": "Rajasthan", "op2": "Uttarakhand", "op3": "Himachal Pradesh", "op4": "Jammu & Kashmir", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who was the composer of the classical composition \u2018Moonlight Sonata\u2019?", "op1": "Ludwig Van Beethoven", "op2": "Antonio Lucio Vivali", "op3": "Arcangelo Corelli", "op4": "George Handel", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following folk dances is associated with Jammu and Kashmir?", "op1": "Jhora", "op2": "Veedhi", "op3": "Rauf", "op4": "Suisini", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a percussion instrument?", "op1": "Cymbal", "op2": "Mandolin", "op3": "Santoor", "op4": "Accordion", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who among the following is an accomplished vocalist?", "op1": "Ronu Mazumdar", "op2": "Shiv Kumar Sharma", "op3": "Satish Gujral", "op4": "Dinanath Mishra", "Answer": 3}]}